Happy Wednesday, 8th February 18th,
2026. You're watching The Program with
Ted Rall and John Kiriakou. Good
morning, John. Good morning, Ted. Good
to see you. Likewise. Welcome back
stateside. No, I'm still in Dubai,
buddy.
>> still in Dubai? All right. Enjoying that
51st first floor view?
Yes, indeed.
And my Dubai
uh Starbucks, and get this, the crown
the crown prince sent over
two enormous boxes of Dubai chocolates.
Watch your weight, John.
>> [laughter]
>> Ted, can you bring that You can bring
that back stateside, right? Will it
travel or will it melt?
>> Most definitely. Oh, yeah. Okay. All
right. I'm going to have stable it'll
stay. Um well, it's good to see you. Uh
I'm glad things are going well over
there. Um so, we're today we're going to
be talking about another big Middle East
story. Uh Jordan is really feeling the
heat. Normally a center of of of
stability almost to the point of being
boring,
uh but now they're they're really
freaking out over there. Jordan freaking
out is not something I don't know about
you, John. I'm not I'm not used to
hearing.
Um
the uh Republicans
are thinking of pulling a nuclear option
to pass this voter ID law. Uh new
unemployment numbers that we may want to
talk to Robbie about um that are super
interesting. Basically, despite
deportations, unemployment is continuing
to go up, but I think it's a more
complicated picture. Um just a little
follow-up from yesterday, we talked
about this situation in France um over
the uh the 23-year-old guy who was
beaten to death um allegedly by members
of the La France Insoumise. We still
don't know if they're really party
members, but we definitely uh they
probably are. Um the police uh has
arrested now 11 suspects in that case.
In France, they tend to round up sort of
extras. So, I think what will happen
here, because in the video it only looks
like it's about seven people who were
involved in the assault. They probably
will arrest the 11, turn the heat up the
French cops are not nice people.
Um, they will beat them up a little bit
and then, uh, you know, get them to turn
on their friends and then, uh, they'll
charge the the six or seven, uh, I think
is the way this is going to go. And
they're going to we're going to think
we're going to find out they really are
all leftists. So, that's only going to
turn the heat up in France. But, I
wanted to just provide that follow-up.
Um, just a little, uh, business, please
like, follow, and share the show. Um,
uh, producer Trent is asking me to
remind everybody that we have, uh,
the, um, t-shirts available for sale.
Everything is up and running. So,
there's the URL. Just go to
deprogram.live.
That's d e pro- program. dot live, and
you'll see it. It's very self-evident.
So, easy a cartoonist can do it. Um,
okay, I think I I think that's it,
right? Um, Robbie, do we have an ad?
Okay, so, Robbie, if you want to pop
that ad up, that'd be great. And in the
meantime, John, you can, uh, we can
maybe answer a question or two, uh, cuz
>> to answer a question. Oh, yeah, please.
>> good question.
Uh, and I'm going to find it here, and
it is from
No Easy Answers. John, big fan, love
Dead Drop, thank you very much. There
are comments on all podcasts with former
CIA officers that say, "There's no such
thing as ex-CIA. What are your thoughts?
What are signs of controlled
opposition?"
There are very few things that I hate
more
than when people say in the comments,
"There's no such thing as ex-CIA." Or,
"Once CIA, always CIA." Like these
mental defectives have any idea how the
CIA does its business. First of all, I
find that to be incredibly
intellectually lazy.
They're going to say I'm CIA. I lost my
freedom. I lost my wife. I lost my
children. I lost my pension. I lost
friends and relatives who walked away
from me
because I'm secretly still in the CIA
and the CIA is paying me to go out there
and criticize them and call them all war
criminals. You're playing the ultra long
game, John.
I believe there are so many
genuinely stupid people out there, but
there are.
Yeah, I think they think that the CIA
>> like to see them tell it Snowden to his
face. Once CIA, always CIA.
Or the sons of Philip Agee who literally
had to move around the globe constantly
to avoid assassination from the CIA
after he left the CIA.
Or Ray McGovern who has devoted his life
to to issues of peace and freedom after
he left the CIA. So anyway, I [__]
hate that more than pretty much anything
else that I encounter. Well, it doesn't
make any sense. It doesn't make any
sense. You by yourself are perfect are a
shining example of how it doesn't make
Yeah, if you want to see if you want to
see like controlled podcasters,
take a look at Sean Ryan.
I mean,
you can look at a dozen different
podcasts where it's clear they're just
sort of spouting the CIA line.
But not the anti-CIA people. Sorry. All
right, John, let's
let's do this ad and then we'll do a
And then we can do that leftover
question about the Constitution from
yesterday. Um okay, here we go. You've
probably noticed Rumble is growing fast
and it's not slowing down. They're
building a real alternative to Big Tech
that puts creators first and actually
protects free speech and now there's
Rumble premium, an easy way to upgrade
your experience. With premium, you get
ad-free viewing across the platform, no
pre-rolls, no interruptions, it's just
the content you came for. Plus, premium
members unlock exclusive content like
bonus videos, behind-the-scenes drops,
and more from your favorite creators.
Right now, Rumble is offering 10 bucks
off an annual subscription. Just go to
rumble.com/premium
and use the promo code studio at
checkout. That's rumble.com/premium
promo code studio, no ads, more freedom
and content you actually care about.
That's the deal. And just weirdly, um if
you just do the $5 a month thing, uh
John and I get it all. Um but if you do
the $10 a month thing, we share it with
like everybody across the platform. But
you do you. Uh if you do the $10 though,
you get to see everything. So, that's
just but you know, that's that's what's
going on. Um John, there was this
question yesterday. Uh Robbie, you have
this question. So, if you can just maybe
about the Constitution.
Yeah. Is there
Sorry, I caught you while you're in the
middle of swallowing something. Well,
well, he's
swallowing laughing laughing gunner. He
made me do it.
No, it happens. No, it was a a email
that we got from from a friend of the
show. He said, "Hi Robbie and Ted. Uh
I have a question for you and you John
and Ted. In the episode titled uh
shutdown scramble, in the episode, Ted
says the Constitution's outdated and
needs to be rewritten from scratch. John
agreed. When John responds to Ted's
comment, he repeats that he felt the
Constitution was outdated. My question
is,
why do you feel that way?
And could you explain on why you feel
that way?
Right.
John, you want to go first? Yeah. I
think I went first last time, so There
are lots of parts of the Constitution
that I think are
either O B E,
overtaken by events,
or need to be seriously updated. Do we
really need the third amendment? You
know, I even saw a political cartoon the
other day saying, you know, we've fought
for the first amendment, we've fought
for the second amendment, now it's time
to fight for the third amendment. Well,
the third amendment is that you can't
quarter foreign troops in your home.
But do we really need that? Although I
don't know
we might have to worry about quartering
domestic troops in our homes.
Right. Um I think that Supreme Court
decisions over the over the decades
have weakened the fourth and the sixth
amendments. I think that they need to be
rewritten and strengthened. I think the
fifth amendment, frankly, needs to be
strengthened. Agreed. And and um
and we need an equal rights amendment.
Uh a majority of a large majority of the
states have an equal rights amendment.
Almost two-thirds of the almost uh
three-quarters rather of the states
have their own uh equal rights
amendments in their state constitutions.
So, you know, and we've we've got a an
amendment
>> of the Electoral College while we're at
it?
>> Get rid of the Electoral College, first
thing you do. Absolutely.
Because it's not a democracy to have an
Electoral College. I I would also
strengthen the first amendment. Right
now it only covers you if you're
targeted by a by a by a public
institution like a the government. But
you should be covered your employer
should not be able to fire you because
of something you say not at work.
That's right. So you should be covered
for that. The first amendment needs to
be strengthened. Um probably needs to
include a federal shield you know, a
federal shield law type constitution. Um
I would if you're going to keep the
second amendment, I would clarify it and
define it to
so that we know which arms are covered,
which arms are not covered. Make a
distinction if we're going to between
military and non-military weapons. Uh
but you know, avoid like so we just can
make things clear.
Yes. I I agree with all of that, Ted.
Um I I think I think the cons- Yeah, I
mean Oh, and the most difficult thing is
the amendment process is so complicated
and so onerous. I mean, it's almost
impossible to amend. Um and I think I
would I would also make impeachment
probably a lower bar. It's too hard.
We've never We've had some really [__]
presidents. We've never been able to
remove and convict a single one in the
Senate.
I mean, come on. We should
I mean, it should be easier.
And let me thank Mike Cantu real quick.
He says, "John, I'd be happy to buy you
a new webcam or Wi-Fi extender." Thank
you Thank you. It's unnecessary. This is
my old laptop. I just
grabbed it by accident when I left to
come to Dubai. I'm going to go home I'm
going to arrive home tomorrow morning.
Uh and um
and uh
I frankly I came into a couple of bucks
this week. So, I'm I'm going to buy
myself a a brand new laptop and with a
better camera. But, thanks for thinking
of me. Yeah, so that's good. Uh Robbie,
anything on the Constitution before we
go?
Uh just
Well, I mean,
we got to decide what kind of a nation
are we going are we going to be? Are are
we going to continue pretending that we
are a a federation of sovereign states,
which is what we are currently doing
now,
uh up until Trump decides he's going to
get rid of the last power that states
have, which is voting right law which is
voting laws,
or are we going to become a
a a traditional country like what you
see in Europe?
I mean,
the the whole the whole reason why we
have
>> to have a parliamentary system
um that got if we got rid of the
Electoral College, then we'd be open to
have multiple parties.
Yeah, but if you get rid of the
Electoral College though, then what
you're going to have is that you're
going to have three states who are going
to decide everything for everybody else.
No, no, no, no. No, no, no. As it stands
today,
a candidate can win just 17 states and
win the presidency.
Sure. No, I I believe that
>> got rid of the Electoral College, it
would be by popular vote.
Yeah, the population of the rural states
is also increasing vis-a-vis the
population of the urban states, right?
>> California lost two entire congressional
districts in the last census. That's a
million and a half people.
It's a very different country than the
13 colonies. Um I would just one side
thought I had yesterday that really kind
of chilled me. I'd be interested in
hearing what both of you guys have to
say about it. So, you know, there's been
a lot of speculation. We're going to
talk about the Save America Act that
that the Republicans may be flirting
with coming up with an excuse to cancel
the elections either this one and or the
next one
in order to because they know the
results aren't going to favor them.
Um
I was thinking, you know, at first I was
very focused. Everyone's focused on
2028, but I actually think if I were
going to subvert an election, the one to
start with is this one for the simple
reason like who is going to riot and and
and mix it up with the cops violently in
the streets over a midterm election that
most people don't even vote in.
Yeah, that's a good point.
Yeah, I don't know. I just
I do agree that the Constitution needs
to be replaced. It's
It's outdated. It's for a different It's
for a nation that no longer exists.
It's for a nation that hasn't existed
uh
it for for well over a century and the
system of government that it set up no
longer exists either.
Uh
And if you wanted to find like that's
you Bobby, you always talk about like
are we a confederate of states or are we
a like a European style centralized
representative democracy, right? Again,
the Constitution could clarify that,
right? I mean, you know, for example, if
there's a right to succession, it should
be clearly enumerated in the in a
constitution. Well, it is in the 9th and
10th Amendments. I mean,
here's the here's the part that that
people miss.
The Constitution is a is a document of
negative rights.
It tells the it tell it's supposed to
tell the federal government, this is
precisely what you are allowed to do, no
more, no less.
We are so far beyond that
that it it's insane. Well, it's also
ignored, right? Like, while we're at it,
let's clarify war powers, which, you
know, currently is completely out of
control.
That's right.
No, well, it is Well, I mean, for
example, the FBI.
Where does the Constitution give the
federal government any jurisdiction
whatsoever over law enforcement?
I I can't find
>> Or creating or creating a national
police force. No, it's not there. Those
are the perviews of the states. Yeah,
the Congress in in in the What is it?
The late 19th century, very early 20th
century, whenever it was, Congress
arbitrarily decided that any right
not given states in the Constitution
automatically becomes the purview of of
the Congress. Which is the mirror image
of what the Constitution actually says.
Oh, yeah, I I agree with you. I don't
think the Founding Fathers intended for
for there to be a an all-powerful
central government, but this is the
system we've given ourselves over the
decades. No, I agree. And so, like, for
example, now, I I imagine the both of
y'all have been to Europe. I never have.
I'm I'm a untraveled Philistine. I know
nothing.
But I can guarantee you, at least from
the from the commonest stuff, people in
Europe like, why do the states dictate
dictate voting laws? That's a national
thing.
It's because the systems of governments
are completely different. We were never
set up We The intention was not for
there to be a strong, overriding federal
system that dictates its will to the
states. It was supposed to be the other
way around.
And that would have been the
>> practical considerations for that,
right? In in 1789,
the United States was big and rural and
hard to get around. And you know, even
France, although it's a you know, the
size of Texas, still a much smaller
country, right? So,
you know, it's easier to make it
centralized. Although that didn't really
happen until Napoleon.
Well, also France had a thousand years
of history had a common language had a
common culture.
I mean had a
I mean Well, less common than you might
think. You know, it cobbled together
from a bunch of duchies and
Well, sure, you know, and then you had
of course they didn't have the Brittany
and stuff. I mean but the core of France
though was French like you know, you had
a continuous history going back. Mhm.
Whereas no no the 13 colonies you had
was predominantly English, you had
Irish, you had Scottish. People had
their own different traditions and it
>> But I think geography was really
determinative. Oh, of course it was.
Yeah. Yeah. But the answer the question
I think needs to be replaced.
Okay. All right, thanks Robbie. And I
also think another thing John would
happen if we had a constitutional
convention, just having the discussion
would bring up
things that you and I and Robbie and
other people may not even think about,
but there's considerations that people,
you know, needs and desires that the
American people should have the ability
to air and maybe have enshrined in a
constant new constitution.
Um Can you imagine Ted if there were a
new constitutional convention?
The overwhelming pressure that the
drafters would be under by corporations,
special interests,
>> Insane. Israel. Cuz Israel would want,
you know, any criticism of Israel equals
anti-Semitism and a felony enshrined in
the constitution.
>> Punishable by death. Yeah.
>> Yeah. No, it's true. I mean, yeah, the
the level of
That's that's part of the problem,
right? Is that like
our our politicians are so incredibly
corruptible and purchasable for like low
amounts of money.
And there would be so they would be
overwhelmed. I mean, it would be
impossible
for anyone except maybe someone like a
Rand Paul to resist.
Well,
yeah, no, that's that's impossible.
All right, John, let's talk about um
I guess we're on this topic. Shall we
talk about the Save America Act and then
we'll get into the into the questions.
Um the So, it turns out that the Save
America Act currently will has no past
chance of passage in the Senate
unless they do the nuclear option and
they say, "Okay, we're going to break
through the filibuster, ram it through
on a simple majority vote." John
Fetterman, the traitor from your home
state, says that he will vote for
for this. So, basically what happens is
you have to present a passport when you
vote or a passport card, some kind of
proof of citizenship, or you have to
have your birth certificate, which by
the way is the easiest to forge document
in the world.
>> Yeah, there's no picture on it.
>> [laughter]
>> Mine's literally a
a card.
You know, it's it's hilarious.
And they're issued by a bunch of
jurisdictions, so no one knows what a
proper one looks like. It's ridiculous.
But you have to have a birth
certificate, that's good enough. Or you
have to have But like for people who
changed their names, like women who got
married, trans people, they have to go
to court and get a document that says,
"I'm the same person who's on this birth
certificate." Who's going to do that to
choose between the crappy Republicans
and the crappy Democrats? Nobody. I
wouldn't. It's like I don't know, it's
not worth it. I'm not going to bother.
>> No, I agree with you. So, the point is
this is a this is a this is not just
simply about identifying yourself with a
driver's license and saying, "Okay, that
person is me." Um this is more than
that. It's proof of citizenship, which
is an entirely different animal. I think
a lot of people who haven't been
following this story don't really
understand that. I think if it was just,
you know, identification, probably most
Americans would say that's common sense.
Okay, fine. But [clears throat] uh you
know, this is proof of citizenship. Um
So, which most people just don't have or
many people don't have. Yeah, many
don't. Many is a better way to put it.
So, I mean
>> Well, let me ask you Let me ask you a
question then.
Uh in that context,
in
just about every European country,
certainly every Middle Eastern country,
I can't speak to Asia cuz I'm it's not
my area of expertise, but everybody's
got a national identification card.
Yeah.
The Greeks, I think, were like the last
in the EU
because, you know, the church was
against it. They said it was the mark of
the beast. And then the EU, in all their
infinite wisdom, began the Greek series
with the numbers 666, which just made
the whole thing a joke.
Seriously, I was thinking to myself at
the time it was a catastrophe.
Hilarious. So, um the Greeks finally got
a national identification called card
called a daftotita.
Why are Americans so opposed to a
national ID card?
Um yeah, you know, I mean, I think it's
cultural, right? I mean, it's it's one
of those things like the idea that you
could, you know, like in I don't know
how it is in Greece. I imagine it's the
same in France and in most countries, if
a police officer approaches you and
demands to see your your national ID
card, you have to present it. You have
to have it on you. You don't forget it
when you go out to the store. And if you
don't have it, they can detain you
indefinitely until they determine your
identif- your identity.
You know, that I disagree with very
strongly.
And and I watch these these YouTube and
TikTok videos every single day of what
are called First Amendment auditors, who
will just go they'll they'll wear wear
masks, so all you can see are their
eyes, and they're just standing there
with their cameras mounted to a
to a
stabilization
pole,
and they'll just stand like outside of a
bank.
Or out
side
of
police station. And invariably, somebody
just
and they call the cops come
they "Oh, you're in on, you know,
public property taking photographs.
Okay, have a good day." And they walk
away. But two-thirds of the time, the
cops are like, "Let me see some ID." Uh
and the photographer will say, "Am I
being detained?" "Yeah." "For what
crime?" "Suspicion." "Oh, is suspicion a
felony or a misdemeanor?" "Well, we're
going to see about that."
It's like, "No, cop. You don't know the
law."
Yeah, you just make stuff up. You cannot
demand my ID if I have not committed a
crime, am about to commit a crime, or am
in the process of committing a crime.
Cops in 17 states
they can. In in in 33 states, the cops
cannot demand an ID. They can say, "Do
you mind if I see your ID?" In which
case you can say, "Go fly a kite."
But
I'm opposed to giving cops the authority
to demand ID. With that said, one of the
things that never seeks never, sorry,
ceases to shock me
is how few people actually carry an ID.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, I know that's that's for
sure. You know, I mean, the thing is I
think it's a I think the traditionally
it's been the slippery slope argument,
John. People are afraid that if the ID,
um, is issued, that it wouldn't just be
used to make your life easier so that,
you know, you if you go to the Social
Security office, here I am. If that's
what it was, I don't think most people
would mind. It's actually, I mean, I
like having my French ID.
Parenthetically, um, in France charges
you for a passport, it charges you for,
um, you know, any any travel document
like that. It does not charge you for
the national ID card. That's considered
the French Supreme Court has ruled that
it's your because the state requires you
to have it, it's, uh, you know, they
must supply it for free, no fee. And,
um, I I think, you know, if that's part
of my argument against the, um, Save
America Act. If you're going to require
something, it's basically an unfunded
mandate, right? Like, if you want
someone if you pass a law and say, you
have to have something, then, you know,
it ought to be free. It ought to be
supplied by the I don't think the
government should even charge fees for,
you know, any document like passports.
>> strongly about that. I think all,
um, mandated IDs should be free for
everybody.
Now, they'll say, well, passport's not
mandated, but I mean, come on. You have
you you should have one. So, Like, yes,
yeah. Everybody should have a passport.
>> Everybody should have one. So, um, so
yeah, so I mean, what do you think? Do
you think I mean, the Republicans are
obviously what I wanted to sort of get
your thoughts about the uh politics
here. It looks to me like the, uh, the
Republicans are really, really worried
about this fall. Like, more than even we
thought. And that if they're not talking
about pulling the nuclear option to get
this through,
um,
you know, that's that shows their
desperation because obviously it means
that when the Democrats get back in
charge, the filibuster will probably be
dead. Yeah, it'll be it'll be gone. If
if the Republicans go to the nuclear
option
on this,
it plays directly into the Democrats'
hands. Just like when Harry Reid
went to the nuclear option on federal
judges. Yep.
The Republicans were like, "Thank you,
Harry Reid. Thank you, because we are
going to screw you but good when we're
in charge." And that's exactly what
happened.
So, Donald Trump is on record as being
strongly, stridently opposed to the
filibuster. Mhm. Because it handcuffs
him. And he's been pressuring Republican
senators to go to the nuclear option, do
away with the filibuster, because it's
going to be great for Donald Trump. But
then when Donald Trump's not president
anymore, Then what?
>> there's going to be hell to pay for the
Republicans. The Democrats will be able
to do anything they want.
Anything at all. For sure.
So, yeah, and I would say it's very
short-sighted. You know, every party in
power always thinks it's going to be
like that forever, as we've talked
about.
>> I add one thing, Ted? I I've mentioned
in the past I've got a friend who works
in the White House.
And he told me And I think I've said
this in the past.
This was about 4 weeks ago. He said that
internal RNC polls
show the Republicans losing
40 House seats.
>> I had heard 30. In a best-case scenario,
Oof. the Republicans are going to lose
15.
There was a piece in the Washington Post
yesterday about Abby Spanberger, the new
governor of Virginia, former CIA
officer.
Um
Abby
on her very first day as governor signed
a bill into law calling for a special
election to be held in April that would
allow the redrawing of district
boundaries in Virginia in response to
what the Republicans have done in Texas
and Florida and elsewhere, North
Carolina,
Indiana. Not Indiana, they voted no. But
anyway, you get the idea. Mhm.
It's currently 6 to five Democratic
among, you know, congressional
representatives in Virginia.
Under the new Democratic bill, it would
be 10 to one Democrats.
Donald Trump did this.
He He forced state legislatures to
redraw boundaries, and the Democrats
said, "Okay, you want to do that? We can
do that, too." They redrew New York.
They're going to pick up three more
seats in New York. They redrew their
They are redrawing California. They can
pick up five more seats in California.
They can pick up four more seats in
Virginia. Like, was it really worth it?
Yeah, once you pull up that string, the
whole the whole thing unravels.
>> Exactly. The whole sweater comes
unraveled. Didn't we say ages ago that
um
that what the Republicans are doing is
they're just re-implementing
the 1980s boundaries.
Right before Congress decided to redraw
everything to make incumbent safe.
So, instead of heading having turnovers
of 40, 50, 50, 60 seats, which were not
unusual, we're getting turnovers of
three, five, you know, 10 seats. I love
the law of unintended consequences. It's
one of my favorite things. Um it drives
history. Uh yeah, so we'll we'll
continue to follow that. Um do you think
the Do you think the Republicans will do
this before we move on, John? Do you
think they'll they'll pull they'll
they'll resort to the nuclear option? I
don't.
I think John Thune I think he's a good
leader for the Republicans.
>> He's a traditionalist. He's a
traditionalist, and I think he's going
to stand up here.
And just be like, "No."
Okay. Well, I hope I hope you're right
there. We shall see. All right, and then
we'll we still have you know, the jobs
numbers and and Jordan to talk about.
But let's we should do some questions.
Okay, so thank you for the five Canadian
dollars on YouTube. If electoral college
isn't democracy, then what do you think
of parliamentary democracies where 34%
of the popular vote can form a majority
government?
Well, it's it's a it forms a it forms a
uh
uh plurality government, right? I think
that's a democracy. You What [laughter]
do you think, John? Yeah, I do, too.
Yeah, I do, too. Um you know, because
because I'm so familiar with Greece, I
keep coming back to to Greece.
Um
and you can do it in so many different
ways, right? You can have a
parliamentary democracy that looks that
looks so different from others. The way
the Greeks did it was after decades of
weak coalition governments because there
are so many viable political parties,
you know, six, seven, eight viable
political parties.
What they did is they passed a new
electoral law, I don't know, 10, 12
years ago,
uh where
whichever
party is first past the poll, right?
Whichever party comes in first
gets an extra 50 seats. Mhm. So, they
can form a uh a majority, and they don't
have to ask, you know, the conservatives
are asking the communists to join with
them to fight the socialists, and it's
like you just end up with meaningless,
powerless governments. But there are
there are different ways of doing it.
You know, and in the American context
where, let's be honest, just about every
American is a capitalist. You can be
sort of a
social democrat or a conservative
republican or whatever, but most of us
are capitalists. So, you're not going to
get these extremes that we've seen in
other countries. Like the Greek
Communist Party consistently wins
between 3 and 5%, and that's just enough
to be a splinter in the butt of whatever
party happens to to have the working
majority. That wouldn't be the case in
the United States because we don't have
a viable Communist Party or even a
viable Socialist Party. Not yet and
probably not ever, but yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Um
firmware, thanks for the twofer. Uh
Harry Reid, a giant of the Senate. What?
I think John was being sarcastic.
>> I was. I was being sarcastic. I I'll
tell you what, the literally the only
thing I ever liked about Harry Reid
is
every single time
I would go to a Pete Seeger concert and
I followed Pete all over the East Coast,
Harry Reid was in the audience. That's
bizarre.
Yeah, he loved Pete Seeger as much as I
do or did.
Okay.
>> There are a lot of good questions today,
you guys.
>> All right, let's get let's get let's
let's bang them out, John. Okay,
John, you know where that came from?
Putin one said there's no such thing as
a former KGB man. That's where these
dumbos get that.
>> That is absolutely correct. Yes.
They F U so Kiria thanks for the $2. All
Kiriaku was really replaced by a cyborg
like in Future World. I don't know what
that reference is. I mean I know what
Future World is.
Three Burns one stone, thanks for the
$2. Interested to know if you guys
believe in divine justice and how all
the bullying and killing the US is doing
and backing all over the world will come
back on us one day, maybe soon. Well,
that's called blowback, right?
Yeah. It happens sometimes, not all not
most of the time. Uh
I I would love to believe in divine
justice, but I don't.
I I that's exactly how I feel. I want to
believe that
that karma is is out there,
but I I don't know.
Um don't body doubles exist? Wouldn't
Mark Epstein uh Jeff Epstein, right?
Have incentives to go along with
>> No, Mark Epstein. Mark Epstein. Have you
seen the earprint of Epstein's body? No,
I have avoided the earprint of his.
>> I've I've not seen the earprint, but I
talked to Mark Epstein about 2 weeks
ago.
And
he's I mean, he identified his brother's
body. He said, "Jeffrey Epstein's dead."
But his position is that Jeffrey Epstein
was murdered.
Oh.
Yeah. That's my position too.
Um
Daddy of Triplets, thanks for the 10
bucks. I live in Tampa. There's been a
large and loud increase of activity in
the skies coming from MacDill Air Force
Base. Sounds like the military action is
not too far away. Thoughts?
Yeah. Yeah. Um
I think that the Pentagon is preparing
for the worst
uh in Iran. I think that we should take
these pronouncements by the Pentagon and
the White House very seriously. God
knows they are out here in the garden.
>> going to handle that at the same time as
Cuba collapses? Yeah.
Be careful what you wish for. Yeah,
seriously. Um James Cain, would a
conflict between Israel and Turkey
be the end of NATO?
That's a good question.
>> That is a very good question.
An attack on one is an attack on all.
We should give that thought. That's
worth writing about. Yeah, let's think
about that. Let's come
Let's come back to that like later in
the week. All right. All right, we'll
we'll we'll we'll we'll cogitate on
that. That's one of those things you
have to have running in the background.
>> There's also a question from Aman.
Um
he says that there's that there's fear
in Aman about uh this concept of greater
Israel.
Well, let's talk about that then. Hey,
I'm I'm I'm worried about this. So So
basically, um Israel is moving to fully
formally annex the West Bank. I mean,
you know, it's pretty much all but done,
but now they're going to sell the
colonists um you know, Palestinian Arab
land. Um and so, I don't know again how
that works legally when you don't have
the original deeds to that land in the
first place. I guess you just make it up
and you stamp a star of David on the top
of the deed and and call it a day,
right? But, um, so that means the
Jordanians currently, kind of like, if
you look at the map, they have the West
Bank as kind of a buffer zone between
them and Israel proper.
Um, that will no longer be true. They'll
have the Zionists right up on their ass,
right on the banks of the Jordan on the
river, right like right up there on the
Allenby Bridge. Um, and, you know,
that's making the Jordanians nervous.
They think that basically the the the uh
intent of the Israelis is to make life
so miserable for the West Bank residents
that they're going to many of them be
pushed out and uh there'll be a a
migrant ex um pow flow into Jordan. Uh,
and thus, you know, and we see anybody
who watches Zionist propaganda online
knows that that's the dream, right? They
They Zionists always argue, "There is a
Palestinian state. It's called Jordan.
And they should take all the
Palestinians and we want all of uh
historical Israel, as they call it, and
Samaria and Judea to for themselves.
They don't want to share with the
Palestinians." So, um, the the Jord- So,
you know, normally
a stable Jordan has been a
cornerstone of American foreign policy.
And now, uh it looks like the Trump
administration isn't paying a lot of
attention Yeah. to the kingdom, right?
And um and the Jordanians are getting
[__] nervous as [__] And if Jordan
goes, I mean, that's a I mean, that's a
stalwart. I mean, that would be a real
problem.
It's hard to even know what would happen
as a result. I'm genuinely worried about
this. You know,
There's somebody at my door. I
apologize. Okay.
>> Hold that thought. Okay, I will I will
hold that thought. Let me see if there's
like a Here, I'll I'll bring in Robbie
so I have I have company here.
Um
hey hey
Robbie. So, Robbie, let's talk about
immigration. I know you have thoughts
about that.
Um
no. So so um new new new jobs numbers
are out. Um last year between 200,000
and a million immigrants, that's a big
range and so it's funny that that range
is so big, but basically stopped working
according to the US Census Bureau.
Either they got fired, they quit their
jobs, or they or they were deported,
right? Um but
they left, but unemployment for uh you
know, people like you and I who are born
here in the US
jumped from 4.1 a year ago to 4.7%
uh this last month in January.
Um that's not only higher than the
overall unemployment rate of 4.3,
but even higher than the 4.6 for
foreign-born workers. Um
we thought, and you and I have I've
argued this at your side, um oh, let me
put John back on here. John, we're
talking about the jobs numbers. Um
and basically the idea is that uh
removing we thought we would think that
like getting rid of uh illegal
immigrants would open jobs for
native-born Americans and that their
unemployment rate should at least stay
stable.
Um and anyway, it's the American the
American Enterprise Institute, which is
right-wing, says that basically the
deportations cause a reduction in demand
and with uh and since consumerism drives
2/3 of the economy,
that has caused an un uh a surprising
increase in unemployment among those of
us who are, you know, native-born US
citizens.
Now, there are other explanations for
all this, but what do you guys think?
Well, I think I think there's something
to that. Go ahead, Robbie.
I think it just comes to I think that
the big canary in the room is wages.
Just because these jobs come open,
if they don't pay enough you actually be
able to pay your bills,
why would you do that?
I mean, that ultimately is the issue. Is
until until labor
is recalibrated actually have real
value,
people are not going to take these jobs
because they can't afford to. Yeah. I
mean, you're I mean, why would you
>> Robbie, the the same Republicans who say
what you say
are the ones who were were bitching
about inflation during the Biden
administration essentially threw all the
Democrats out. Nobody wants to pay $20 a
pound for chicken. But if you fire all
of the Ecuadorians who work in the
chicken
plants or whatever they call the chicken
places, the chicken processing
processing plants,
um, and you replace them with Americans
and you have to pay them wages that
Americans will take that terrible work
for,
nobody's going to be able to buy
chicken.
But how do we know? We haven't tried.
Biden tried in that he allowed prices to
rise. If you raise if you raise wages
in order to attract native-born
Americans into those jobs that
immigrants have right now,
nobody's going to be able to afford
anything.
Yeah, but here's the difference, though.
I
I think here's probably a
the conflation and this is probably
needs to be
actually its own its own episode maybe
with Achilles.
Inflation is the expansion of the money
supply.
It's not rising prices. Rising prices
are are a symptom of it. What inflation
does that it destroys the purchasing
power of every dollar that's in
existence because you're
creating more dollars. So, what do you
do to combat rising prices then?
The the only thing that you can do is
that you have to push wages up. And
that's the one thing
Here's the problem with wages up doesn't
reduce inflation.
No, it'll increase inflation. It
increases inflation.
>> No, my argument my argument is that it
doesn't matter. That as long as
inflation doesn't get out of control, as
long as people's uh wages are increasing
faster than than prices, it's fine.
Yeah, but that's the problem right now
is that wages wages are stagnant.
They've been stagnant for 20 years.
And immigration
you know, is a is a key factor of that.
That there's a reason why both political
parties want immigration. Guys, I think
there's something else going on. I think
that like uh this one year long
experiment in mass deportations is it's
too early to tell as as Joe Lie would
say. I mean, you know, so if you're if
you're an employer who has a bunch of
low wage jobs that are going empty going
wanting because there's no one to fill
them right now.
Yeah, maybe right now you can hold
tight, but eventually you're going to
have to come to Jesus and you're going
to have to pay more and hire someone.
Yeah, you have to.
I mean, I I think it's sort of like it's
sort of like the housing market. When
the housing market starts to go down and
then but you know, people who own houses
don't want to drop their housing price.
They don't want to sell at a loss and
they just hold those prices and then no
nothing's being sold until eventually
people have to move and they have to
sell and then they just but it takes a
while. Not to mention also
generally speak the tariffs and AI are
having pushing with
pushing unemployment higher. I mean, I
think we're slowly
sliding into a
very slow moving recession.
I think that I think we've been in a
recession now for a long time. It's just
the government's lying about it.
Well, we had a stagnant economy, but we
But I mean, the specific definition of
inflation it's it's consecutive quarters
with negative economic growth. Yeah,
it's but you you can't falsify these
numbers.
Well, I mean,
for example, depending on where in the
country is that you live,
you could definitely be in a local
recession. Oh, yeah, yeah. You can go to
Washington DC or something. Yeah, okay.
I grew up John and I grew up in local
recessions. We're still in recession
since the '70s. I mean, go to Ohio, it's
dead. Montana's toast. I mean, we're
screwed. Don't talk about those
Californians who are leaving California.
Yeah, I know. These [__] are coming
here and they need to stay away. Yes,
you would. And if you own a Dow a Dow
index fund, you're a happy man. Yes,
exactly right.
>> Hey, Pam Bondi's happy. Look at the Dow.
Look at the Dow. Screw Main Street.
Right. Seriously.
I mean, is that the Is that the kind of
government we want? I don't. Well, I
think again, polls seats, is it? Right?
I mean, the the economy is not
I don't see any signs of improvement in
the pipeline in the next few months. No.
And it's not like the Democrats have any
new ideas. No.
No. They're just going to benefit
because when in a two-party system, when
you're pissed, you vote for the party
out of power. That's all. It doesn't
mean we like the party out of power. It
just means we're we're trying to express
our anger here.
That's it. And they're not even mad.
They just don't care.
Hey, uh
I want to thank Sodan for his uh for
another $20. Sodan, you're so incredibly
generous to us. Thank you. And he's got
a he's got a question as to where we
think Epstein would rank as an
intelligence asset. Was he better placed
than the Cambridge 5, Ames, and other
foreign assets? And did he do more
damage than Kim Philby?
I'm going to I'm going to take a first
chop at that. I'm going to say
the Cambridge 5 were better placed
because they were literally at the top
of MI6. Um Ames was
is incredibly well placed that it did
lasting damage. Ames was the head of
counterintelligence at the CIA
for the Soviet branch, which later
became the Russia branch.
Uh and 12 CIA assets were executed
because of his treachery.
And
you know, Philby
I mean, Philby was recruited in college
and directed to join MI6. And he became
the deputy director of MI6.
Uh I think I think that
that Epstein has been damaging, but not
like those guys. Those guys were
damaging in at historic levels.
There is absolutely nothing I could add
to that, and so I'm not going to try.
Um
Danwell, here in Cyprus, there are
hundreds of aircraft using Andreas
Papandreou
um Papandreou uh air base
>> Andreas Andreas Papandreou. Papandreou,
yeah, air base in Cyprus. Could this be
the big preparation for the invasion of
Iran? Also, a huge US contingent in RAF
Akrotiri. Yeah, the the RAF
the the British have just sort of lopped
off this giant chunk of Cyprus and just
won't give it back. But we wouldn't do a
ground invasion. We would do it would be
an aerial bombardment campaign.
>> And and those and those are air bases in
Cyprus. Yeah, Akrotiri is the British
air base. The Americans also have an air
base.
Cyprus is also used as a uh
as a site for evacuations. So, if
Americans need to be evacuated from from
Lebanon or from Israel or even Jordan,
they're normally flown to uh to Cyprus.
You know, take that with
the
the information that we just heard a
moment ago about increased air activity
over Tampa coming out of MacDill Air Air
Force Base
with the second aircraft carrier battle
group steaming uh to the uh Persian
Gulf.
This is bad. You know, I'm watching CNN
International all day long and they're
saying that
the US and Iran came out of the second
round of talks in Geneva yesterday and
both said positive things.
That's fine for today.
But when the aircraft carrier battle
group, the second one, gets to the
region in the next 10 days or so,
shit's going to get ugly. I hate to say
it.
Agreed.
Um and let's see. Uh okay, so um
Ish Mustafa, follow up from Amman. Are
you hopeful of a peaceful integration of
different Middle Eastern cultures? I've
seen a vicious cycle of hatred here,
which really perpetuates the regional
issues.
I agree with that completely.
Um
this is something that
Well, the question is is there going to
be a Are you hopeful of a peaceful Are
we hopeful of a peaceful integration? I
would say.
I'm I'm I'm not. I'm not hopeful of a
peaceful I mean, sure. I I Yes, I hope
there could be a peaceful integration. I
think there won't be.
Yeah. Yeah. And you know, part of the
reason why no other countries want
Palestinians
is not just because they've got this
bias against Palestinians, which they
do,
but it's also because
it gives the Israelis an out.
And the Israelis say, "Oh, you're
willing to take Palestinians? Here, take
more." And next thing you know, there
are no Palestinians in Palestine
anymore. Well, let's talk about that.
You were you had to go answer the door
uh when we were just starting to talk
about Jordan. Um
I thought this was a really big [__]
deal. What What do you think? Yeah, I
agree.
I agree. This is a very big deal. Oh,
and that Thank you for raising that.
There was a point I wanted to make.
When the Israelis and the Jordanians
were negotiating their peace treaty
decades ago.
Uh and they finally agreed and they
signed.
The Israelis went to the Jordanians and
said, "Listen, in the spirit
of honesty and peace,
we want you to know we've been
incrementally stealing your land for
decades."
And what the Israelis were doing
was at night, in the dark of night, they
would move the border fence like a foot
at a time. Just a foot.
So that the Jordanians never noticed.
But you do this over the course of
decades and they had taken something
like 150 m
of Jordanian land that was now inside
the Israeli
border. That's [__] hilarious. And
moved the fence back. The fence back.
Yeah. It's nuts. It's like it's sort of
like in the suburbs where, you know,
there's no there's no fence and your
neighbor you can sort of tell where the
property line is cuz it's where people
cut their lawn and and they cut it at
slightly different level and then, you
know, you notice one one dude he kind of
goes 6 in over the next time he cuts his
lawn and he's like encroaching and the
next thing you know he's up against the
wall of the next house. Yes.
It's true. That is That is [__]
hilarious. So they were they were
working Zeno's paradox?
Yes. All the way to Amman, they were
hoping. Next year in Amman. Next year in
Aqaba.
>> Exactly.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh they're just awful.
They're just awful. Are the Jordanians
raising cane behind the scenes? Are they
uh you know, are they yelling at um you
know, Rubio and saying like, "Cut the
shit." What are they doing? It's not in
the Jordanian character
to to
to just sort of fly off the handle. It's
not. The Jordanians are very diplomatic.
Yeah. They're very behind the scenes.
They don't raise their voices. They
don't
>> They're the fancy ones.
Yeah.
Um if I were if I were a Jordanian
government official, especially one
involved in foreign affairs or defense,
I would be very nervous right now.
Very nervous cuz none of this is good
news.
I mean, they had they used to have a you
know, sort of um
they used to have a uh what's the word
I'm looking for? Kind of a worky
relationship with Israel. Oh, yeah. What
happened?
>> peace. Yeah.
It's the Israeli nature just to push and
push and push until somebody finally
pushes back hard.
They just never they never they just
never never leave well enough alone.
Mhm.
Yeah, it it does that is their national
character. John, the first time I went
to Israel, uh they there there were the
I guess it was like they were trying to
uh you know, encourage Israel to become
more of an international like tech
country. And there were these billboards
and TV ads that were encouraging
Israelis Israelis to stop being so rude
on the phone. And so they would be like,
"When you pick up the phone, don't just
say what?"
>> [laughter]
>> Say, "Hello.
What can I How can I help you?"
You know, you see that in traffic in
Israel, too. I have driven I've told you
before I've been to 72 countries. I've
driven in almost all of them.
And I have
I've encountered certainly worse traffic
than I've encountered in Israel. I've
never encountered ruder drivers.
Like just driving with one finger out
the window, right? Or beeping literally
the nanosecond that the light turns
green. Screaming at each other. It's
like, "What are you doing?" Yeah,
they're [__] maniacs.
>> to stroke out. Relax. Yeah, they're
maniacs, totally. Yeah. It's And I've
driven in some pretty wild [__]
places like India and Pakistan. Yeah.
Afghanistan. Yeah.
I love driving overseas. I feel like
it's not to be missed. Any opportunity
to get a rental car and you know, get
some strange Bulgarian rental car that
you don't know where all the
you know, where the horn is or anything.
>> Yeah. It's like I will not miss that.
And and to drive a stick, it's the only
way to stay in practice driving a stick.
I learned on one and you know, now I
don't have one and I miss it. Um
Ahmed by 9 HU is asking if you're paid
by Cutter.
Uh no, but I would very much like to be
paid by Cutter. They have lots of money.
If you know somebody you can introduce
me to, I'm all ears. Yeah, and if
there's any money left over after John,
I'll take some, too. Okay. Um Great. Uh
John and Ted, have you heard anything
about how Jermall Thomas is doing? I've
I've I've texted Jermall. Oh good. I'll
do the same.
>> he seems to be he's promising to be back
on the air soon. He's doing better. He's
recovering. I think
it was you know, basically he doesn't
seem to think he's in great shape, but I
think he's in better shape than he
thinks he is. I think he sounds better
than he thinks he sounds. I think
there's been like a loss of confidence
since his mini stroke, but I think he's
going to be okay. Um you know, I'm not a
doctor, but he's on the mend, I think is
the right is the right way to put it.
>> [snorts]
>> Do you know where he is, Ted? Um I think
he's back home. He's he's stateside.
He's back he's near you.
Oh good, good, good. I'll give him a
call when I get home.
Cool. Cool. Okay, and back to Cutter,
too.
In all seriousness,
I want to do this speaking tour of the
Gulf in October.
I would love it if Cutter Airways would
agree to be one of my sponsors. So if
anybody knows anybody out there before I
start calling in
some chips,
let me know.
Uh question for you, John. Have you ever
been stopped by the tough tish in
Kuwait.
No.
What is the tough tish?
>> No,
you know, I'm I'm when I'm in Kuwait,
I'm always accompanied by somebody from
the Kuwaiti government. I've never had
any
I've never had any issues at all. What
is the tough tish? Is that the secret
police? What is it? Yeah, it's kind of
like the the
government police, yeah.
Okay.
So, okay.
Um all right, let's see what other
Oh, so let's see. I guess
Yeah, I So, I guess we all right, let's
see what other questions there are here.
Oh, question from Akmad.
Why do you hate Reza Pahlavi?
Cuz he's a clown and a pretender.
And he there's nothing Iranian about
him. And he's from a family of thieves.
And he's not very intelligent. And I can
come up with a half a dozen other
reasons why I don't like him.
Uh You know, another I'll I'll tell you
another reason. He [__] his brother's
wife.
And his brother was so upset that he
committed suicide.
And uh
Don't kill yourself for a over a woman.
Never again.
>> I I can't respect a person like that. I
just can't.
>> Um Let's talk God is asking what do you
think America's biggest strength is?
Great work. Hope you get that pardon,
John. That's a great question. It's a
great question. I think it's our
multiculturalism.
It makes us a stronger country.
Yeah, it brings in a lot of ideas and
I agree with that. Ideas and concepts
and industries from all over the world,
different cultures.
Monoculturists tend to be weaker, I
would say.
Um you know, but also man, that
geographic positioning is to die.
You know, I mean, we have you know,
know, there's all these theories about
like you want north-south big
north-south rivers not big east-west
rivers like China has because you go you
can trade through different climatic
zones.
You want you know, we're protected by
two giant oceans to the east and west,
two allied states to the north and
south. We're separated by thousands of
miles of of water.
We have incredibly rich natural
resources. Also, we haven't been sucking
nutrients out of the land for thousands
of years the way the Chinese have or the
Europeans have. Um
>> Yes. So, I the fact that it's a new,
big, well-situated country counts for a
lot.
Yes.
Yes, I agree.
Uh
let's see here. Oh, sorry. I see that
there's new comment up. Let me get it.
Okay.
Uh
I'm just spitballing here, Laughing
Gunnar says, but you two should do a
comic book release.
Okay. Okay. If only there was someone
here who knew how to draw cartoons. I
know, right?
>> [laughter]
>> So I sent you some pictures, by the way.
>> Yes, thank you. I'm going to be drawing
I will be drawing that.
Okay.
All right. So, I think we are pretty
much ready to wrap it up here. Uh I'm
going to do if we have 1 minute, I want
to call your attention, Ted, to this uh
Randy Fine, Representative Randy Fine,
uh the the newest member of Congress
from Florida, Republican of Florida, won
a special election.
Um he really stepped in it yesterday
when he tweeted that if he had to choose
between Muslims and dogs, he would
choose dogs.
>> God.
And then he doubled down on it, refused
to retract the statement. Democrats are
just apoplectic about this. There's talk
of censuring him, of impeaching him. He
just refuses to back down. One of the
more sickening aspects of this
this kerfuffle
is that literally not one single House
Republican
said publicly that he shouldn't have
said that.
Quite a few chimed in on X. I've been
following this all day yesterday.
Uh sort of a lot of main a lot of
quote-unquote mainstream Republicans
agreed and like basically they tried to
spin it like don't [__] with our dogs,
man. Yeah. He didn't say that nobody
should be allowed to own a dog. He was
he was criticizing people who said that
we shouldn't. No, that's not what he
said. He said that we shouldn't have
dogs.
>> ever said that we shouldn't have dogs.
Yeah. Uh-huh.
Yeah. Yeah, loser.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, who else hated who hated dogs?
That was Thomas Jefferson.
And it is funny too. Like I there were
some Muslims on my feed who were like,
you know, they are objectively unclean.
I'm like, yeah, they eat their own [__]
So, yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> They do. But they are but they're cute
as [__]
Um anyway, so it that's all that really
matters. Oh, Dem will, really quickly,
Dem will. I'm going to be in Cyprus for
10 days in May. I'm going to speak in
both um
Nicosia and
wherever the wherever the Cypriot
diaspora convention's being held.
10 days.
Hope to see you.
All right, guys. That's it for us here
today. We'll be back tomorrow, Thursday
at 9:00 a.m. Eastern Time for the show.
[clears throat]
Please stay tuned for a TMI with me and
Manila Chan coming right up right now.
If you're on Rumble, go search radio and
see you on the other side. If you're on
YouTube, you got to go look for us.
Thanks a lot. See you tomorrow, John.
Uh Ted, I'm flying in tomorrow.
Uh okay, so are you
are you are you indisposed? I'm going to
email you. I think I'm going to get back
just in time for the second half.
Uh okay. Well, well, yeah, email me. All
right, or text or whatever. Okay, bye.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Mhm.